Guide to the International Conference on Gnosticism Audiorecordings
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
International Conference on Gnosticism audiorecordings
1978-1983
RU 187
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
The materials consist of audiotapes of panel discussions, plenary sessions, public lectures, and working seminars of the International Conference on Gnosticism held at Yale in 1978 and in Springfield, Missouri, in 1983.
International Conference on Gnosticism ( Yale University 1978)
Yale University. Department of Religious Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by panel discussion title.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of audiotapes of panel discussions, plenary sessions, public lectures, and working seminars of the International Conference on Gnosticism held at Yale in 1978 and in Springfield, Missouri, in 1983.
Gnosticism -- Congresses; Meetings; Audiotapes
- Audiotapes of the panel discussions of the International Conference on Gnosticism, 1978; Accession 1996-A-005
  Scope and Contents
  Tapes are dubs of originals. Missing tape 1 of both the Seminar on Sethian Gnosticism and the plenary session of March 29. Microcassettes are European manufacture of a proprietory size that does not fit the microcassette player in Historical Sound.
  - Seminar on Sethian Gnosticism
    - Sethianism, Judaisim, and Zoroastrianism, 1978 March; audiocassette (Box 1)
    - Existence of a Sethian Gnostic Sect, 1978 March; audiocassette (Box 2)
    - The Sethian Theological System, 1978 March; audiocassette (Box 3)
    - Sethianism and the New Testament, 1978 March; audiocassette (Box 4)
    - Summary and Conclusions on Sethianism, 1978 March; audiocassette (Box 5)
  - Plenary Sessions
    - 1978 Mar 29, audiocassette (Box 6)
    - 1978 Mar 29, 2 audiocassettes, audiocassette (Box 7)
    - Tardieu, Michel, Helmut Koester, and Elaine Pagels, 9:00-10:30, 1978 March 30; audiocassette (Box 8)
    - Pagels, Elaine and Joel Fineman, 11:00-12:30, 1978 March 30; audiocassette (Box 9)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 9U)
    - Aland, Barbara and Chairman Meeks, 2:30-4:00 p.m., 1978 March 30; audiocassette (Box 10)
  - Public Lectures
    - Chadwick, Henry, "The Domestication of Gnosticism", 1978 March 28; audiocassette (Box 11)
    - Quispel, Gilles, "Gnosis and Psychology: Self-Experience and Projection in Gnosticism According to Jung and His School", 1978 March 29; audiocassette (Box 12)
    - Colpe, Carsten, "The Challenge of Gnosticism for Alchemy, Philosophy, and Literature", 1978 March 30; audiocassette (Box 13)
    - Bloom, Harold, "Lying Against Time: Gnosis, Poetry, Criticism", 1978 March 31; audiocassette (Box 14)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 14U)
  - Working Seminar on Gnosticism and Early Christianity, Springfield, Missouri
    - Layton, Bentley, 1983; audiocassette (Box 15)
  - Unidentified, Undated; audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 16)
  - Unidentified, Undated; audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 17)
  - Unidentified, Undated; audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 18)
  - Unidentified, Undated; audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 19)
  - Unidentified, Undated; audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 20)
  - Unidentified, Undated; audiocassette (microcassette) (Box 21)